Hello friends, my name is Akshay and
welcome to the Inko group channel.
Friends, in today's video we will
talk about the best health insurance plans
and first of all we will
see that if we have to select a health plan then
what are the parameters
that we should consider first. So
let's go to the first point. The first
point is that friends, you will first have to
decide what type of
health insurance plan you want. There are
many helplines in this like family
floater plan, individual plan,
senior citizen plan, reference plan, so from this you have to
select
which type of helpline you
want. Most of all there are two very famous plans in this
like the first one is individual plan
and the second one is family floater plan and
individual plan. So whatever cover you take,
that cover can be used only for your hospitalization or other
activities. If you
take a cover of Rs 3 lakh on recognition then you can use that
plan only for your hospitalization or
your day care activities,
but if  If you are a family member, that is, you have
one or two
kids around you, then my opinion is that you should
go with a family floater plan
because whatever cover you take in a family floater plan
and whichever
family members you insure under that policy, then that
particular cover can be used by your family members
on a sharing basis. But
one more thing to note here is that if
you take a family floater, then
please do not subscribe to your friends in it and you should
please subscribe to your friends
because friends, if you all take a family floater
plan, then the premium is decided on the basis of the oldest person who insures in that floater plan.
Therefore,
if you include your parents in your family floater, then
theirs will
obviously be very high, and your
free insurance will also come out to be very high.
Therefore, if you have parents or
senior citizen parents, then
always take a set health insurance cover for them. The
second parameter that comes up is the policy
premium end.  Sum Insured: Whenever you
buy a policy, first of all you should check
how much coverage is there in the market for the PM you are investing in, but
this does not mean that you should buy a very cheap plan
and it also does not mean that you should
buy a very expensive plan because if you
take a cheap plan then it is possible that there will be only a
few recharges in it or the terms
and conditions will be such that you will
not know right away and as far as sum insured
is concerned, friends, I would like to comment on one thing
that all the individuals should take a
cover of Rs. 3 lakh for themselves and if there
is some then a cover of Rs. 2 lakh will be good for them, so let us
assume that you and your family have
one or two members, then
you should understand that if there are two members then Rs. 22 lakh i.e. a total of Rs. 10 lakh. The next point is
friends, claim settlement ratio.
From the claim settlement ratio, you can find out how many
claims have gone to the health insurance company from which you are taking your policy and how much
claim they have made out of that.  It has been settled and how many claims have been
rejected, but
friends, here it is used, the
meaning of settlement is that if you are
claiming even ₹10 and
get approval for ₹50,000, then it will be
considered as settlement, if a company says
that their claim settlement ratio is 90%, then it does
not mean at all that if you make a
claim of ₹10, then you will get nine lakh
rupees, this claim
settlement ratio is a complete parameter
and it is used only in comparative analysis,
and if the CSR of any company is 90%, then
it is considered good, but
you can never do any design only on the basis of CSR, the
next point comes, their
at place of, its simple meaning is
that how much money does your health insurance company
earn and
how much money does it spend from that earned money, such
plane so expenses by the British, we
call them trim pressure  And if it
is 72.92 percent then it is quite good but
if it is 90% or above 100% then
it means that she has spent more than she is earning, so
how can we believe that her future will be
good. Before moving on to the next point, I have
a request for you that if you
are on my channel then please do
not forget to subscribe to this channel and if you
liked this dish video and
want videos in favor of this method then do
not forget to like this video and move on to the next
point. The next point is friends, take
action by taking cashless facility. Friends, many
companies claim that they have
7000 specific or 10,000 hospitals in their network,
but we have nothing to do with their network of 10,000 or 10,000 hospitals.
We have nothing to do with how many
hospitals are there in your location in which you
can use sweater TV. Or if you have
a prepaid hospital nearby, then whenever you
do this, then check this.  Whether
that hospital is covered under your policy or
not, only then you should select any plan. The
next topic is room rent. Friends, there are
many policies in which this technique was being used
that you can pay one percent of your sum insured as
your room rate. Let us
assume that you have a
cover of five rupees, then the room you take should
not cost more than 5000 rupees per day. So
please friends, never take such room rent
plans because
whatever expenses will be incurred on that room after that,
you will have to pay it on a rota basis.
Whenever you go for a loan, you should take such decisions
in which there is no room rent deduction. The
next point is PM post
hospitalization expenses. Whenever you
come for any hospitalization,
in many cases it happens that you have to pay
doctor visit charges first, after that it is
possible that you may have to pay your own
expenses, so all these are
hospitalization charges, this should be
covered in your policy and post
hospitalization charges should also be covered
and in this, minimum  If you are
looking at the hospitalization charges, then the
minimum hospitalization charges should be
improved in your case and
post hospitalization should definitely be Rs 98100.
Next point comes friends, no claim
bonus was given which we also
call primitive response. It is also called front team
response. So, in many helplines,
if you do not make any claim for one year, then
your
cover is increased next year. Suppose
you have taken a cover of Rs 5 lakh, then there are
many such fans that if you have made no
claim, therefore in one year, by
taking Rs 5 lakh, in the next year, your cover will be Rs 10 lakh or Rs
7.5 lakh. So,
you have to keep in mind that whatever plan you have, there
must be a no claim bonus in it, but if there is
no no claim bonus in your plan, then
you must definitely get front team discount.
This means that if
I do not make any claim in this year, then in the next year
when I get the policy renewed,
I should get a discount on whatever cream is there. So,
both of these  One of the benefits
must be there in this plan. The
next point is pre-existing
Divya friends, this is a very important
point and you must check it in every plan.
If you already have a plan
and you know that
you will have to pay hospitalization charges in the next one or two years,
then please
go to your plan and check
what is the waiting period for his periods.
Mostly, the
waiting period for pre-existing diseases of the plans is from
two to five years
and the determination will be
that if there is a waiting period of one to three years
for periods, then you should
select the plan. The next few points which you
must check are the first one,
ambulance charges and your plan
must have an ambulance. The next
most important point comes friends, take
care, so seriously, there are many such plans
who will sometimes give you a plan. If
you are hospitalized for necessary reasons, then do
not take such a plan at all.  This is
because there are many such 30 minutes
which are part of 24 hours for which admission is not required,
like dialysis which takes
four to five hours, so please
if you are taking any cover then you
must check whether all the
treatments are covered in it, half of it,
along with that alternative treatment is also
covered in it, like I will benefit,
or if you take homeopathic treatment
then share the plan with you
that homeopathic treatment
is also included in the benefits, next important
point friends, from the mechanic which is the company, this
is optional and friends, there are many plans in
which there is a waiting list for maternity also,
so you should check all these points
that there is no waiting list for maternity, only then
you should go and
take that bank if you want maternity benefit
and after that friends, this
list is clearly checkup, there should be one free complete checkup in a year
in your plan and the next is the most  The
payment is important friends, there are many such
schemes in which whatever is in the word,
it is done at 20%, you have to pay 20%, so
we call such plus fans,
so you should not take such a fan in
which there is payment, you should
take such a plus in which it is
clearing all the expenses, the next
most important point is the two restoration
benefits, there is a lot of money friends,
if you take a cover of 5 lakhs and
spend your ₹3 in this year, then you have
only 2 lakhs to spend for the whole year,
so in that case many
tabs or almost all the plants have started doing this that
whenever you take your first
treatment, hospitalization and
whatever expenses are incurred, out of 5 lakhs, 3
lakh rupees are spent, then the remaining 2
lakhs is also given back by breaking the relationship
at 5 lakhs, so
even in the remaining year, if you take any treatment
till the end of the decision, then  That claim will also be
settled for you. Whenever you go to
buy a plan,
definitely check its restoration benefit and if you are
also looking for super top up and top facility, then
please always click on the super top up date. So
these were some points friends,
before buying a policy, you must
check it and compare it
with other policies, but it depends on your makeup, it completely depends on
every individual, what are
their
requirements and which plan
suits them, but I personally like the
taste very much for my family,
I will share that with you, so on Rs 200 skin, you
can see that from my two favorite
plans, the first one is the Chot plan which is of
Neevra Health Insurance
and the second one was Life Time Helpline which was of
Money Pass Chikna, both of these have very
good balance, which you should also check. If you
look at the CSR of both of them, it is
90% which is quite good, there is no room rent
limit, no typing  There
is no restoration cover in this. You can see
that it is worth Rs 5 lakh in the city, unlimited
times in a year and
15x unlimited times for lifetime health. This is its restoration
cover which is quite good. Secondly,
you get a benefit that you
get a no-claim bonus of Rs 2.5 lakh, which means
you get a no-claim bonus of 50%.
But in lifetime health, you do
not get any no-claim bonus. Obviously, there is
no logon bonus in this.
But then, it is like that
whatever its limit is, whatever its
restoration is and whatever other different
benefits it has, it is quite good and is of top
standard in this entire
industry. If we look further, then there are many more
hospitals in these two,
that payment option is not there in both.
Prince's hospitalization notification is of a very
good number of countries. See,
in this, you are covered in treatment and detailed statement.
Hospitalization at home is also
included. Ambulance charges are also included
in both of these for the periods which  The waiting
period for this plan is Life Enjoy This plan is
only two years, which is very
magnificent, and the
waiting period for this plan is
3 years, so it depends on you
which plan you want to select. There is
no maternity cover in both plans.
If you want to take maternity cover, then
you can check other plans. And
talking about additional features,
free health checkup is provided in both plans, once in a while, which is a
very good
thing. Alternative medicine is also
provided in both plans. And in the health plan,
friends, you get a
discount of 230 percent and
renewal premium, which is a very good
benefit. So friends, these were the plans which
I like, but it is up to you to select
which plan you like within your criteria. So,
friends, you must have found today's video informative
and very knowledgeable too. So,
similarly, informative  And for those who are
with our team for knowledgeable videos, till then
friends
stay happy and healthy and keep investing, Jai
Hind.